BEN FANNING

FULL-STACK ENGINEER

ABOUT

Full-stack engineer with 5+ years experience working in Javascript/ Typescript (React) & Ruby (Rails). Attended worlds #1 coding bootcamp in 2017 then returned as a lecturer. Co-founded Hoxton Digital, a London web development agency with clients ranging from individual entrepreneurs to medium sized enterprises. Joined Gen H in 2021 to gain experience working for a large company and tackle novel challenges within a mature codebase. Currently freelance.

CONTACT

- www.benfanning.dev
- fanning@hey.com
- https://github.com/fanninggg
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/ ben-fanning/

EXPERIENCE

PRODUCT ENGINEER | GEN H | AUGUST 2021 - DECEMBER 2023

- Led the 5 month implementation of a product switching functionality, a crucial service allowing us to retain clients beyond their initial mortgage term expiration. Team size of 6 people.
- Successfully identified and addressed customer drop-off points in our core user journey by leading the design and implementation of an optimised onboarding flow and customer dashboard. This initiative resulted in a 24% reduction in drop-off from the dashboard landing page after 3 months.
- Mentored junior developers on a range of topics including Rails, React, Typescript & Sorbet.
- Founding member of social committee, headed up the organisation of 3 company parties for 90+ people

FOUNDER & LEAD FRONT-END DEVELOPER | HOXTON-DIGITAL | JUNE 2018 - JULY 2021

- Alongside leading the front-end team, responsibilities also include building client relationships, project management, overseeing UI/UX design sprints & junior developer mentorship.
- Shifted focus to React Native and helped train fellow developers in order to meet client demands for mobile applications.
- Implemented a move towards SMART goal setting for junior developers.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER | DOWN TO PLAY | FEBRUARY 2018 - JUNE 2018

- Wire-framed, designed and built the front-end for Down To Play, an IOS & Android app built in React Native communicating with a Ruby on Rails API via Redux.
- 10,000+ downloads, >80% user retention rate, 4.9 star rating, briefly #1 paid sports app on UK app store.

LECTURER | LE WAGON LONDON | MAY 2018 - PRESENT

- Developed the ability to teach essential coding knowledge at varying levels of understanding. Very helpful when mentoring junior devs.
- Taught core programming topics such as MVC, OOP, ORM & Relational Databases.
- Managed the planning, architecting, implementing and debugging of students final projects. In total, 16 teams led.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF PLYMOUTH | PLYMOUTH | 2012 -2015

- Bachelor of Science, 2:1
- International Relations & Politics